BASHYER SAUD BIN SARAAN

Saudi - Riyadh

+966557798270 Br.1999q@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Information Technology Specialist with 3+ years of expericence in major companies, my objective is to seek an opportunity within an organization, where I could demonstrate my current capabilities and expand it further. Also to gain more knowledge and experience.

My aim is to strive for the best, deliver better services the organization on all level, learn and improve existing knowledge, skills, ability.

I have unlimited ambitious to be part of our National 2030 vision journey by carrying out my positive motivation and make markable achievements in my life.

On personal perspective I'm always flexible, smooth and having energy which will allow me to do multiple different tasks and creat an Initiative ideas and finding/ obtaining solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILL

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

- Java, HTML, CSS, C++, SQL, XML.
- Mastered in Troubleshooting & proplem solving.
- Network Configuration.
- Creative Thinking Skills

-Saudi Council of Engineers Accreditation 2021

-ITIL 4 - 2022

- Front-End & Back-End Development.
- Communication & Excellent interpersonal skills.
- UX/UI

EDUCATION

Diploma of InformationTechnology

2017 - 2019

Princess Nora Bint Abdulrahman University with GPA 4.25 /5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Specialist

July2021-Oct2022

Emircom consultant for TAHACOM Technology and Security Comprehensive Control Company.

Possessing an acute attention to detail and an aptitude for quickly identifying solutions, I am highly experienced in troubleshooting issues, resolving technical problems, and providing efficient and professional User service.

- Receive and analyze internal and external users requests and complains.
- Raise and escalate any general issues and follow-up resolution.
- Comply with defined processes and update tickets within SLA.
- Add, delete, or update user account information, reset passwords in Active Directory
- I Possess extensive knowledge of setting up and installing desktops, printers, networking hardware, IP telephones, and software applications. Adept in troubleshooting any hardware or software issue that may arise.

• Key achievement

- Maintained a 99% end-user satisfaction rating through excellent interpersonal skills and quick problemsolving.
- Completed trouble tickets 25% faster than other desktop support engineers, demonstrating high efficiency.
- Contributed to the knowledge transfer platform by creating comprehensive Service Desk operation documentation.
- Became a trusted personal through high-level problem-solving skills. Solved customer issues with 15% more success than the company average.
- Consistently exceeded monthly KPI for closing end user requests/issues during entire employment.

Ericsson, project with Mobily operation center

- Receive and analyze external users requests and complains related to billing, services.
- Demonstrated proficiency in assigning tickets to appropriate teams and providing diligent follow-up to ensure prompt issue resolution.
- Kept abreast of system information, changes, and updates.
- Conducted impact and gap analysis to evaluate the effects and identify discrepancies.
- Adhered to the Escalation Matrix by promptly raising and escalating issues, resulting in timely resolution.

IT Support Internshipt

Tatweer Education Holding Company

Feb 2019- May 2019

- Setting up and installing new/old computers, Printers, network equipment, IP telephones, and software.
- Installing and configuring operating systems.
- Analyze problems with the service and resolve the issues.
- Network Administration/ Security / Support.
- Resolving all issues coworkers have with their ITsystems and software.
- Educating coworkers about network security and best practices for computer usage.